Register of the Hong Kong subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Hong Kong subject collection
1845-2016
91027
Hoover Institution Archives
116 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (51.2 linear feet)
Corporation annual reports, serial issues, bulletins, newsletters, pamphlets, clippings, press summaries, election campaign literature, other printed matter, videotape and sound tape reel recordings of television and radio news broadcasts, and memorabilia relating to political, social and economic conditions in Hong Kong, and especially to business, finance, education, social services, and governmental administration.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991, with increments received in subsequent years.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Corporation annual reports, serial issues, bulletins, newsletters, pamphlets, clippings, press summaries, election campaign literature, other printed matter, videotape and sound tape reel recordings of television and radio news broadcasts, and memorabilia relating to political, social and economic conditions in Hong Kong, and especially to business, finance, education, social services, and governmental administration.
Business enterprises--China--Hong Kong.; Finance--China--Hong Kong.; Hong Kong (China)--Politics and government.; Hong Kong (China)--Economic conditions.; Hong Kong (China)--Social conditions.; Education--China--Hong Kong.; Social service--China--Hong Kong.; Elections--China--Hong Kong.; Video tapes.; Audiotapes.
- COMMERCE, 1964-1992 (Boxes 1-20)
  Scope and Contents note
  Reports, journals, magazines, newsletters, brochures, statements of accounts, leaflets, survey, financial fact books, commemmorative edition, proposal, intelligence reports and bulletins, arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Allied Investors Corp., 1971-1976 (Box 1)
  - Allied Properties (H.K.), 1988
  - American Chamber of Commerce, 1991
  - Amoy Canning Corp., 1979-1983
  - Asian hotelkeeper and catering times, 1982
  - Associated Hotels, 1973-1982
  - Atlas Industries, 1981-1984
  - Bank of East Asia, 1974-1981
  - Cathay Securities, 1974
  - Cavendish Co., 1988-1989
  - Century City Holdings, 1986
  - Cheong Sun Development Co., 1981-1982
  - Cheung Kong, 1980-1988
  - Chiap Luen Enterprises, 1976-1980 (Box 2)
  - China Engineers, 1973-1978
  - China Entertainment and Land Investment Co., 1975-1985
  - China Light and Power Co., 1975-1990
  - China Motor Bus Co., 1979-1990
  - China Provident Co., 1974-1978 (Box 3)
  - China Underwriters Life and General Insurance Co., 1981
  - Chinese Estates, 1976-1988
  - Chuang's Consortium, 1990
  - Chuang's (Holdings), 1975-1985
  - Chung Wah Shipbuilding and Engineering, 1989-1990
  - City and Urban Properties, 1973-1976
  - City Resources (Asia), 1989-1990
  - Crocodile Garments, 1972-1986
  - Dairy Farm International, 1988-1989
  - Eastern Asia Navigation Co., 1976-1980 (Box 4)
  - Estate Finance, 1976-1985
  - Executive (Hong Kong), Sept. 1990
  - Express Finance and Investments, 1979-1980
  - Far East Consortium, 1988-1989
  - Far East Holdings International, 1989
  - Far East Hotels and Entertainment, 1979
  - First Pacific Holdings, 1987
  - First Pacific International, 1987
  - Fountain Set (Holdings), 1990
  - Friends of the Earth (Hong Kong), 1990-1991
  - Furuma Hotel Enterprises, 1985
  - General Bottling Co., 1972-1980
  - Goodyear Estates, 1979-1980
  - Grand Marine Holdings, 1980
  - Great Eagle Co., 1975-1987 (Box 5)
  - Green Island Cement Co., 1978-1987
  - Hang Lung Development Co., 1978-1983
  - Hang Seng Bank, 1974-1981
  - Haw Par Brothers International, 1974-1980
  - Henderson Land Development Co., 1987
  - HK-TVB Limited, 1987-1988
  - Hoe Hin Pak Fah Yeow Manufactory, n.d (Box 6)
  - Holian Investments, 1988-1990
  - HongKong, Inc., 1990-1991
  - Hong Kong Accountant, 1991
  - Hong Kong Aircraft Engineering Co., 1971-1988
  - Hong Kong and China Gas Co., 1973-1988
  - Hong Kong Association of Accounting Technicians, 1991
  - Hong Kong Business, 1990
  - Hong Kong Ferry, 1988
  - Hong Kong Industrialist, 1990
  - Hong Kong Institute of Surveyors, 1991
  - Hong Kong Port Development Board, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Hong Kong Productivity Council, 1990
  - Hong Kong Shell Inc., 1988
  - Hong Kong Shippers' Council, 1990
  - Hong Kong Telephone Co., 1974-1987
  - Hong Kong Tourist Association, 1990-1991
  - Hong Kong Trade Development Council, 1987-1990
  - Hongkong and Kowloon Wharf and Godown Co., 1974-1985
  - Hongkong and Shanghai Banking Corp., 1974-1989 (Box 8)
  - Hongkong and Shanghai Hotels, 1974-1989
  - Hongkong and Whampoa Dock Co., 1970-1976
  - Hongkong and Yaumati Ferry Co., 1964-1985 (Box 9)
  - Hongkong Electric Co., 1971-1973
  - Hongkong Electric Holdings, 1976-1989
  - Hongkong Engineering and Construction Co., 1979
  - Hongkong Land Co., 1973-1988
  - Hongkong Land Group, 1980-1982 (Box 10)
  - Hongkong Realty and Trust Co., 1974-1989
  - Hongkong Telecom, 1990
  - Hongkong Tramways, 1970-1972
  - Hopewell Holdings, 1974-1987
  - Hutchison International, 1975-1976
  - Hutchison Properties, 1976
  - Hutchison Whampoa, 1982-1990
  - Hutchison-Boag, 1972-1980
  - Hysan Development Co., 1987
  - IBI Asia, 1988
  - Inchcape Enterprises, 1976-1981
  - Institute of Seatransport, 1990
  - International Industries, 1983-1987 (Box 11)
  - International Maritime Carriers, 1980-1989
  - Island Peninsula Realty and Enterprises, 1979-1984
  - Jardine Matheson and Co., 1975-1989
  - Jardine Matheson Holdings, 1984-1988
  - Jardine Securities Co., 1973-1983
  - Jardine Strategic, 1988
  - K. Wah Stones, 1987
  - Ka Wah Bank, 1980-1987
  - Kai Tak Land Investment Co., 1979-1980
  - Keng Fong Sin Kee Construction and Investment Co., 1982-1985
  - Kowloon Motor Bus Co., 1966-1984 (Box 12)
  - Kowloon Shangri-la Hotel, 1990
  - Kowloon-Canton Railway Corp., 1990
  - Kumagai Gumi (Hong Kong), 1988
  - Kwong Sang Hong, 1978-1988
  - Lai Sun Garment Co., 1984-1985
  - Lane Crawford Ltd., 1970-1988
  - Lap Heng Co., 1979-1987
  - Lee Hing Development, 1979-1987
  - Liu Chong Hing Investment Co., 1988
  - Loan and Investment Co., 1971-1976 (Box 13)
  - Local Property Co., 1979-1987
  - London and Pacific Insurance Company, 1988-1989
  - Mai Hon Enterprises, 1974-1980
  - Management Studies Society, 1991
  - Mandarin Oriental International, 1988-1989
  - Mass Transit Railway Corp., 1989
  - Melbourne Enterprises, 1983-1985
  - Metro-Dodwell Motors, 1975
  - Nan Fung Textiles Consolidated, 1979-1987
  - Nanyang Cotton Mill, 1974-1985
  - New Town Properties, 1983-1988
  - New World Development Co., 1976-1989 (Box 14)
  - Ocean-Land Development, 1978-1989
  - Orient Overseas, 1987
  - Orient Overseas Container, 1973-1979
  - Overseas Trust Bank, 1977-1983
  - Paul Y. Construction Co., 1979-1986
  - Peninsula Group Magazine, 1988
  - Pioneer Industries, 1983
  - Planning and Development, 1990
  - Pokfulam Development Co., 1980-1990 (Box 15)
  - Port Development Board Hong Kong, 1991
  - Promet Petroleum, 1984-1987
  - Public International Investments, 1989
  - Realty Development Co., 1974-1989
  - Regal Hotels, 1985
  - Safety Godown Co., 1982-1987
  - San Imperial Corp., 1972-1973
  - San Miguel Brewery Co., 1974-1989
  - SEA Holdings, 1989
  - Shui Hing Co., 1974-1981
  - Shun Tak Enterprises Corp., 1988
  - Sincere Co., 1975-1989 (Box 16)
  - Sincere Insurance and Investment, 1978-1979
  - Sing Tao Newspapers, 1983-1984
  - Singapore Hong Kong Properties Investment, 1972-1973
  - South Sea Textile Manufacturing Company Ltd., 1973-1984
  - Southern Pacific Properties, 1973
  - Stelux Holdings, 1987
  - Sun Co., 1975-1979
  - Sun Hung Kai and Co., 1983-1988
  - Sun Hung Kai Properties, 1973-1989
  - Sun Hung Kai Securities, 1978-1986 (Box 17)
  - Swire Group, 1991
  - Swire Pacific, 1973-1989
  - Swire Properties, 1977-1980
  - Tai Cheung Properties, 1975-1982
  - Target Financial Service, 1990
  - Target Intelligence Report, 1990
  - Taxation Institute of Hong Kong, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Textile Alliance, 1975-1977
  - Trafalgar Housing, 1984-1989
  - Union Bank of Hong Kong, 1979-1989
  - Unison Knitting Factory, 1990
  - Wah Kwong Properties, 1974-1987
  - Wah Kwong Shipping and Investment Co.(Hong Kong), 1974-1982
  - Wardley Ltd., 1988
  - Wharf Ltd., 1988-1989
  - Wheelock Marden and Co., 1974-1980
  - Wheelock Maritime International, 1974-1976
  - Wing Hung Kee Investment Co., 1980 (Box 19)
  - Wing Lung Bank, 1988-1989
  - Wing On (Holdings)., 1981
  - Wing On Co., 1974-1988
  - Wing On Life, 1974-1979
  - Wing Tai Development Co., 1979-1987
  - Winsor Industrial Corp., 1975-1984
  - World International, 1980-1984
  - Yangtzekiang Garment Manufacturing Co., 1988
  - Zung Fu, 1975-1988 (Box 20)
- CITIZENSHIP, 1990 (Box 20)
  Citizenship registration application and guide, leaflet, information kit, draft Hong Kong Order and press release. Includes material written in Chinese.
  - British nationality selection scheme
  - Form BN (HK) 1
  - General guide to the British nationality selection scheme, 1990
  - Hong Kong is our home, 1989
  - Hong Kong Order, 1984 and 1986
- EDUCATION, 1927-1993 (Boxes 20-22)
  Bulletins, newsletters, newspapers, memoranda, magazines, prospectus, research report, advertisement, journal, college manual, yearbook, university calendar, career guide and report on education. Some of these materials are partly in Chinese.
  - Chinese University of Hong Kong, 1986-1991 (Box 20)
  - Chu Hai College, 1987-1989
  - City Polytechnic of Hong Kong, 1984-1991
  - Hong Kong advanced level examination, 1990
  - Hong Kong Baptist College research report, 1989-1990
  - Hong Kong Education Department, 1990
  - Hong Kong Institute of Language in Education, 1988-1989
  - Hong Kong Polytechnic School, 1991
  - Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, 1987-1992 (Box 21)
  - Journal of the Hong Kong Tertiary Institution
  - English Writing Competition, 1989-1990
  - Lingnan College, 1989-1991
  - St. Clare's Girls' School, 1927-1990
  - St. Stephen's Girls' College, 1988-1990
  - Dialogue, 1989 (Box 22)
  - Hiso, 1984
  - Hong Kong Education Department, 1988-1989
  - Hong Kong University convocation, 1986-1990
  - Hong Kong University Students' Union, 1987-1990
  - Hong Kong University 80th anniversary, 1992-1993
  - University of Hong Kong, 1986-1987
  - University of Hong Kong, 1988-1992
  - Witman Digest, 1991
  - Zhongshan University, n.d
- GENERAL FILE, 1982-1991 (Box 23)
  Leaflets, brochures, news summary, sports publication, prospectus for the performing arts, souvenirs, speech, magazine, journals, newsletters, reports, summary of editorials, newspapers, forecast of visitors, legislative council questions, information regarding the relationship between the central government and the local entities, clippings, and materials about the government information services and the House of Commons. Parts of these materials are in Chinese.
  - City news, 1991
  - Daily summary of newspapers by London office, 1988-1989
  - Hong Kong Academy of Performing Arts, 1986-1987
  - Hong Kong Dragon Boat Festival international races, 1985-1987
  - Hong Kong Government Information Services, 1988-1990
  - Hong Kong Journalists Association, 1990-1991
  - Hong Kong Library Association, 1988
  - Hong Kong Monitor, 1989-1990
  - Hong Kong Postmaster General, 1989-1990
  - Hong Kong Profile, 1982
  - Hong Kong Sports Institute, 1991
  - Hong Lok Yuen news, 1991
  - Miscellaneous press clippings
  - Opinion, 1988
  - Upbeat, 1990-1991
  - Urban Services Department, 1988-1989
  - Young Reporter, 1990-1991
- ECONOMIC CONDITIONS, 1982-1992 (Box 23)
  Bulletins, consumer price index, report, official publications and newspapers.
  - Building Prosperity, 1989
  - Consumer price indexes, 1982-1988
  - Hong Kong China I, 1991
  - Hong Kong Economics Society, 1990-1991
  - Hong Kong Economic survey, 1989-1990
  - Hong Kong Institute of Economic Science, 1989-1990
  - Office of the Commissioner of Insurance, 1990-1992
- POLITICS AND GOVERNMENT, 1974-1992 (Boxes 24-26)
  Newsletters, government lists, map, daily press summaries, electoral ordinances, membership application, brochures, bulletins, reference papers, magazine and official records of Hong Kong urban council.
  - Basic Law, 1988-1989 (Box 24)
  - China for Affirmative Action, 1988-1992
  - Daily press summary, 1986
  - Daily press summary, 1986-1987 (Box 25)
  - Daily press summary, 1988-1989 (Box 26)
  - Chinese press summary, 1988-1990
  - Government Airport Core Programme (ACP)
  - Great Britain, Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs, 1987-1990
  - Guide to the Legislative Council elections, 1985
  - Hong Kong civil and miscellaneous lists, 1988
  - Hong Kong Democratic Foundation, 1990
  - Hong Kong district board electoral boundaries map
  - Hong Kong electoral provisions ordinance, n.d
  - Hong Kong Foundation, 1990-1991
  - Hong Kong Urban Council, 1973-1974
  - Legislative Council behind the scences, 1987
  - Office of the Executive and Legislative Councils, 1988-1990
  - Political Science Association, 1991
  - The Friends of Hong Kong committee, 1992
  - United Democrats of Hong Kong, 1990
  - White papers, 1988-1991
- HUMAN SERVICES, 1985-1990 (Box 27)
  Newsletters and reports.
  - Against child abuse, 1988-1989
  - Birthright Society, 1987-1989
  - Caritas, Hong Kong, 1989-1990
  - Central Registry of Drug Abuse, 1981-1990
  - Christian Family Service Center, 1990
  - Christian Service News, 1990
  - Family Planning Association of Hong Kong, 1989
  - Hong Kong Association for the Mentally Handicapped, 1990
  - Hong Kong Coroners Report, 1989
  - Hong Kong Down Syndrome Association, 1990
  - Hong Kong Housing Authority, 1985
  - Hong Kong Journal of Gerontology, 1990
  - Hong Kong Journal of Mental Health, 1989
  - Hong Kong PHAB Association, 1988-1990
  - Hong Kong Social Security Appeal Board, 1985-1986
  - Methodist Epworth Village Community Center, 1988-1989
  - Pamphlet on Community Services, n.d
  - Society for the rehabilitation of offenders, 1989-1990
- LABOR AND LABORING CLASSES, 1981-1983 (Box 27)
  Leaflets, proceedings and newsletters.
  - Hong Kong Christian Industrial Committee, 1981-1983
  - News, views and comments on labour matters, 1983
  - Sha Tin District Board, 1988-1989
  - Tsuen Wan District Board report, 1983-1984
- LAW ENFORCEMENT, 1988-1991 (Box 27)
  Newspapers and reports.
  - Director of Legal Aid, 1990-1991
  - Hong Kong, Criminal and Law Enforcement Injuries Compensation Boards, 1989
  - Royal Hong Kong Police, 1990-1991
- RELIGION, 1990-1991 (Box 28)
  Bulletins, newspapers and pamphlets.
  - Chinese Coordination Center of World Evangelism, 1991
  - Diocesan Echo: The Diocese of Hong Kong and Macao, 1990-1991
  - Hong Kong Catholic Church Directory, 1990-1991
  - Hong Kong Islamic Youth Association, 1990
  - Hong Kong Muslim Herald, 1990-1991
  - Sunday Examiner: Catholic news of the week, 1990
- SECURITIES INDUSTRY, 1987-1991 (Box 29)
  Bulletins and daily quotations.
  - Stock Exchange of Hong Kong, 1987-1991
- TECHNOLOGY, 1989-1991 (Box 30)
  Brochures, journal, leaflets, newsletter, news weekly, and reports.
  - AMP Products Pacific, 1989-1990
  - Computerworld, 1990
  - Datacom News, 1990
  - Daya Bay, 1989
  - Education Technology, 1991
  - Guangdong Nuclear Power Station, 1989-1990
  - Hong Kong Engineer, 1990
  - Quality and Certification, 1991
- CHINESE LANGUAGE PUBLICATIONS, 1984-1991 (Boxes 30-31)
  - Reports and newspapers
- Rest of collection not yet described (Boxes 32-118)